<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.Loganavter.Improve-ImgSLI</id>
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <name>Improve ImgSLI</name>
  <summary>Image comparison with magnifier</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Improve ImgSLI is a versatile open-source tool designed for detailed side-by-side image comparison. Easily spot differences and inspect fine details using its synchronized magnifying glass feature. Ideal for designers, photographers, AI art/upscaling enthusiasts, and anyone needing precise visual analysis.
    </p>
    <p>Key features include:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Compare images with an adjustable horizontal or vertical split line.</li>
      <li>Use the powerful synchronized magnifier with flexible controls: adjustable capture/display size, position control (mouse and WASD/QE keys), view freezing, and combined magnifiers.</li>
      <li>Load single or multiple images per comparison panel via drag-and-drop or file dialogs.</li>
      <li>Easily switch between loaded images using dropdown selectors.</li>
      <li>Save the complete comparison view (including split line, magnifier markers, and optional filenames) as a full-resolution image.</li>
      <li>Swap image lists between panels with a single click.</li>
      <li>Edit displayed file names directly within the interface.</li>
      <li>Multi-language interface (English, Russian, Chinese, Brazilian Portuguese) with persistent settings.</li>
      <li>Selectable interpolation methods for the magnifier (Nearest Neighbor, Bilinear, Bicubic, Lanczos).</li>
      <li>Quick preview of individual images using Space + Mouse Buttons.</li>
      <li>Improved performance with image caching.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      The application is intuitive and distributed under the free MIT License.
    </p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/Loganavter/Improve-ImgSLI</url>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.Loganavter.Improve-ImgSLI.desktop</launchable>     
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Loganavter/media_archive/1.7.0/Improve_ImgSLI/screenshots/screenshot_1.png</image>
      <caption>Vertical caption</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Loganavter/media_archive/1.7.0/Improve_ImgSLI/screenshots/screenshot_2.png</image>
      <caption>Horizontal caption</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Loganavter/media_archive/1.7.0/Improve_ImgSLI/screenshots/screenshot_3.png</image>
      <caption>List option</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <developer id="io.github.loganavter.Improve-ImgSLI">
    <name>Loganavter</name>
  </developer>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <releases>
    <release version="7.9.0" date="2025-10-27">
      <description>
        <p>This update represents a strategic unification effort, bringing significant architectural improvements, powerful new workflow features, and a complete suite of image analysis tools.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Shared Toolkit Integration: Complete integration with a shared component library enabling code reuse across projects and establishing a solid foundation for future development.</li>
          <li>Clipboard Integration: Revolutionary workflow enhancement with full clipboard support! Paste images directly from your clipboard using Ctrl+V, with an intuitive direction selection overlay for choosing placement (left/right/both).</li>
          <li>Professional Image Analysis Suite: A comprehensive set of visual comparison and analysis tools, including pixel difference highlighting, structural similarity mapping, edge detection, channel analysis, and metrics calculation (PSNR/SSIM).</li>
          <li>Enhanced UX Customization: Complete redesign of visual customization options, allowing precise control over the comparison divider and magnifier separator (visibility, color, thickness). System notifications on Linux have been fixed.</li>
          <li>Premium Magnifier Rendering: Subpixel precision controls ensure smooth, accurate comparisons even when images have different resolutions. The magnifier now intelligently adapts its rendering quality based on zoom levels and comparison modes.</li>
          <li>Robust Multi-Platform Builds: Extensive DevOps work ensured stable cross-platform deployment, with thorough testing and debugging across Linux (AUR, Flatpak) and Windows build systems.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="6.2.0" date="2025-08-16">
      <description>
        <p>This is the most extensive architectural refactoring in the project's history, transitioning the entire application to a robust and modern Model-View-Presenter (MVP) pattern. This update establishes a new, stable foundation for future development and introduces a completely custom-built UI.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Complete Architectural Overhaul: The codebase is now fully modular and based on the MVP pattern, significantly improving stability and maintainability. Many underlying bugs have been passively fixed as a result.</li>
          <li>New Custom UI: The third-party `PyQt-Fluent-Widgets` library has been removed and replaced with a custom-built set of "fluent-style" components. This removes GPL licensing constraints and gives the application a more unique design.</li>
          <li>Enhanced Image List Management: The image selection flyout is now a powerful two-panel manager with full drag-and-drop support for reordering and moving images between lists.</li>
          <li>New and Reimagined Dialogs: Introduced a dedicated, feature-rich Export dialog and a redesigned, easier-to-navigate Help window.</li>
          <li>Improved Caching: The caching system has been upgraded from two to three levels for even smoother performance during interactive use.</li>
          <li>Reduced Package Size: The removal of the external UI library has decreased the application's plus size on some platforms.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="5.8.20" date="2025-07-09">
      <description>
        <p>This is a major quality-of-life and rendering engine update.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Overhauled the core update logic to a reactive, state-driven architecture, significantly improving stability and eliminating a class of race-condition bugs.</li>
          <li>The magnifier can now render outside the image boundaries and correctly handles horizontal split view.</li>
          <li>Added smooth, anti-aliased borders for the magnifier and capture area for better visual quality.</li>
          <li>Added long-press actions for swapping and clearing images/lists to speed up workflow.</li>
          <li>Image selection dropdowns are now scrollable with the mouse wheel.</li>
          <li>Added a new setting to permanently enable or disable debug logging.</li>
          <li>Replaced all internal print statements with a structured logging system.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.9.0" date="2025-06-05">
      <description>
        <p>This release introduces a major user interface overhaul and performance improvements.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The application interface has been completely redesigned using the modern `qfluentwidgets` style.</li>
          <li>The image caching service has been significantly improved, resulting in a much smoother experience.</li>
          <li>Refactored the core rendering code for better performance and easier maintenance.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.1.9" date="2025-04-15">
      <description>
        <p>This release focuses on settings persistence and bug fixes.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added window state persistence: the app now remembers its size and position between sessions.</li>
          <li>Introduced a new Settings dialog to centralize application preferences.</li>
          <li>Added options to configure UI language, JPEG save quality, and the maximum length of displayed filenames.</li>
          <li>Addressed several critical bugs to improve stability.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
